Guide to the Autograph Files, 1669-1995
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- L
  - Leach, Abby, 1898-1901; (3 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Leacock, Stephen, undated; (1 postcard)
  - Leaf, Emily, [no year] Jan 26; (1 letter)
  - Learoyd, H.J., 1910 Mar 30; (1 letter)
  - Lee, Robert E., 1865 Apr 10; (2 letter facsimiles) (Box 1)
  - Lee, Sidney, 1902-1903; (2 letters)
  - Lefeuer, Jacob, 1894 Dec 12; (1 letter)
  - Lefevre, Madeleine Shaw, undated; (1 letter)
  - Lehman, Henriette Blanding, 1961 Dec 16; (1 letter)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1932-1946; (5 letters)
  - Lehr, Kathleen Pawle, undated; (1 letter)
  - Leoke, Hans, 1923 Jun 18; (1 letter)
  - Leonard, Clair, 1940-1992; (5 letters, 1 envelope, 1 page of notes)
    — Includes letters from Helen Maguire Muller.
  - Leonard, Elle S., 1885 Sep 2; (1 letter)
  - Leonard, William Ellery, 1921-1923; (4 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Levertov, Denise, 1968 Dec 19; (1 letter, 1 card)
  - Levy, Jullien, [no year] Sep 24; (2 letters)
  - Lewis, Dio, 1865-1883; (2 letters)
  - Lewis, Eleanor (Lord), 1916 Nov 18; (1 letter)
  - Lewis, John L., 1936 Nov 13; (1 letter)
  - Lewis, Leo Rich, 1910 Sep 27; (1 letter)
  - Lewis, Lloyd, 1930 May 16; (1 letter)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1921-1930; (8 letters, 4 envelopes)
  - Li, Fredrica, 1940-1941; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Ligget, Jeannette M., 1939 Jan 7-23; (4 letters, 2 copies, 3 pages of clippings)
  - Lilienthal, David E., 1949 Nov 10; (1 letter)
  - Lincoln, John Lark, 1875 Feb 20; (1 letter)
  - Lindeman, Eduard C., 1940 Sep 24; (1 letter)
  - Lindsay, Olive, 1945-1947; (4 letters)
  - Lindsay,Vachel, 1919-1930; (3 letters, 1 program, 3 newspaper clippings, 1 card)
  - Listz, Franz, 1846 Jan 16; (1 letter)
  - Littlejohn, Abram Newkirk, 1891 Oct 30; (1 letter)
  - Livermore, Mary Ashton Rice, 1879-1880; (2 letters)
  - Livingston, Margaret Lewis (1783-1860), 1826-1842; -- see Margaret Lewis Livingston Papers
  - Livingstone, Mary, 1959 Apr 2; (1 letter)
  - Livingstone, Richard W., 1959 Apr 2; (1 article with note)
  - Lockwood, Belva, 1892-1902; (3 letters, 3 copies, 1 note, 1 pamphlet cover)
  - Lockwood, Ward, 1940-1941; (2 letters)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1888-1916; (4 letters)
  - Lodge, Jr., Henry Cabot, 1958; (1 letter)
  - Logan, Mrs. John A., 1920 Jan 17; (1 letter)
  - Lomax, John A., 1916 Oct 28; (1 letter, 1 page of comments on a lecture)
  - Long, John Davis, 1959 Apr 2; (1 letter)
  - Longfellow, Alice W., 1901 Nov 7, undated; (2 letters)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1875 Feb 22; (2 poems, 1 copy, 1 signed photograph)
  - Longstreth, T. Morris, 1948 Nov 12; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Lord, F.E., 1889 Sep 28; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Lord, John K., 1889 Sep 21; (1 letter)
  - Lorente, H.A., 1926 Jul 24-Aug 20; (2 letters)
  - Louis Phillippe, Duc d’ Orleans, 1816; (1 page notes)
  - Lovejoy, Owen R., 1917 Apr 26; (1 letter)
  - Low, Josiah O., 1875 Feb 11-15; (2 letters)
  - Low, Seth, 1907 Jan 14; (1 letter)
  - Low, Sidney, 1913-1922; (2 letters)
  - Lowell, James Russell, 1878-1891, undated; (9 letters, 1 poem manuscript, 2 envelopes)
  - Lowell, P., 1893 Mar 13; (1 letter)
  - Lowell, Robert, undated; (1 letter)
  - Lowes, John Livingston, 1933 Jan 23; (1 letter)
  - Lucas, E.V., undated; (1 postcard)
  - Luther, G.S., 1887 Sep 20; (1 letter)
  - Lutz, Alma, 1951-1956; (2 letters, 1 book clipping)
  - Lyman, Charles E., 1922 Apr 15; (1 letter)
  - Lyman, Hannah, 1865-1886; (45 letters, 4 envelopes, 3 copies, 1 funeral pamphlet, 1 cloth item)
  - Lyon, Mary, 1847 May 4; (1 letter)
- M
  - Mabie, Hamilton Wright, 1900 Feb 10; (1 note)
  - MacCracken, Henry Noble, 1959 Apr 2; (21 letters, 1 envelope, 1 newspaper clipping, 1 menu)
  - MacCracken, John Henry, 1916 Jun 16; (1 letter)
  - McCullough, Hugh, 1889 Nov 16; (1 letter)
  - MacDonald, Greville, 1928 Nov 23; (1 letter)
  - MacDonald, Louisa, 1921 Feb 7; (1 letter)
  - MacDougall, Allan Ross, [no year] May 21; (1 letter)
  - MacKaye, Dercy, undated; (1 envelope)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1931-1951; (3 letters)
  - MacLeish, Martha H., 1945 Dec 22; (1 letter)
  - Macleod, H.W.G., 1918 Jul 4; (1 letter)
  - Macurdy, Grace H., 1917-1931; (3 letters)
  - Macy, Henrietta G., 1889-1897; (40 letters, 35 envelopes, 8 postcards)
  - Magill, Edward Hicks, 1871 May 25; (1 letter)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1946; (1 letter)
  - Manly, John M., 1908 Mar-May; (3 letters)
  - Mann, Kate, [no year] Jul 6; (1 letter)
  - Mannes, Leonard, 1951 Nov 2; (1 letter)
  - Mannes, Marya, 1967 Jan 21; (1 letter)
  - Manning, William T., 1919 Jan 15; (1 letter)
  - Mansfield, Charlotte, 1914 Jan 1; (1 letter)
  - Marburg, Theodore, 1918 Dec 13-31; (2 letters)
  - Marchbanks, Hal, 1919 May 19; (1 letter)
  - Marfineau, Harriet, 1846-1854; (2 letters, 2 envelopes, 1 photograph)
  - Marks, Elizabeth, 1915-1916; (3 letters)
  - Marks, Jeannette, 1957 Jan-Aug; (4 letters)
  - Marsh, George Perkins, 1848 Sep 16; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Marsh, Reginald, 1940 Nov 4-22; (2 letters)
  - Marshall, Benjamin T., 1917 Sep 25; (1 letter)
  - Marston, Anna L., 1929 Sep 16; (1 letter)
  - Martineau, James, 1880-1897; (3 letters)
  - Martini, Jean Paul Egide, 1789 Mar 3; (1 letter)
  - Masefield, Constance, 1917 Mar 18; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Masefield, John, 1916-1926; (21 letters, 21 envelopes, copies)
  - Mason, A.E.W., 1914 Jan 6; (1 letter)
  - Mason, Mrs. L., 1888 Jul 14; (1 letter)
  - Mason, William, 1897-1922; (2 letters)
  - Massen, Louis, 1895 Nov 20; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Massenet, Jules, undated; (1 manuscript)
  - The Masses (The Editors of), 1917 Mar-Apr; (2 letters)
  - Matouskova, Julia, 1981 Feb 4; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Matthews, Albert (Paul Siegvolk), [no year] May 23; (1 letter)
  - Matthews, Brander, 1888 Jul 14; (5 letters, 2 envelopes, 5 manuscripts)
  - Matthews, Burnita Shelton, 1950 Apr 29; (1 letter, 1 page excerpts from Congressional Record)
  - Matthieson, I.F., undated; (1 letter)
  - Maulila-Bucena, Lydia, 1945 Apr-May; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Maurois, Andre, 1930 Oct 12; (2 letters)
  - Mayhew, Willmott, 1788 Jul 18; (1 manuscript)
  - Mayo, Mrs. L.O., 1910 Jun 25; (1 letter)
  - Mayor, T.M., 1914 Jan 9; (1 letter)
  - McAdams, Elisabeth M., 1939 Feb-Oct; (3 letters, 4 notecards)
  - McAffee, Mildred H., 1936 May 21; (1 letter)
  - McCarthy, John Russell, 1925 Jul 17; (1 letter)
  - McCarthy, Mary, 1971-1983; (2 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - McClosky, Mark A., 1955 Oct 20; (1 letter)
  - McConnell, Francis J., 1920 Jan 24; (1 letter)
  - McCormick, Cyrus H., 1921 Dec 17; (1 letter)
  - McCormick, Edith, 1921 Oct 26; (1 letter)
  - McCosh, James, 1872-1887; (3 letters)
  - McGraw, Maria (Dickinson), 1912-1917; (10 letters, 8 envelopes, 2 postcards)
  - McIntosh, Claire (Rustin), 1893 Apr 11; (1 letter)
  - McKerrow, Ronald Brunlees, 1934 Mar 3; (1 letter)
  - McLaughlin, Andrew Cunningham, 1898 Nov 7; (3 letters)
  - Mead, Edwin D., [no year] Apr 24; (1 letter)
  - Mechau, Frank, 1940 Nov 18; (2 letters)
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander, 1923-1957; (7 letters)
  - Melchior, Lauritz, 1937 Apr 24; (1 program)
  - Melgs, Louise (Lawrence), 1915 Nov 1-15; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Melville, Lewis, 1906 Aug 11; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Mencken, H.L., 1921-1924; (9 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1840 Aug; (1 letter)
  - Menon, Lakshimi N., 1961-1963; (3 letter)
  - Merrill, J. Warren, 1888; (1 letter)
  - Merritt, Jesse, [no year] Sep 21; (1 letter)
  - Meyer, Agnes, 1958 Oct-Nov; (2 letters)
  - Meyerbeer, Giacomo, undated; (2 letters)
  - Middleton, Robert, undated; (1 letter)
  - Mikhailovich, Aleksei, 1669 May 4; (1 charter of grant) (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Milinowski, Marta, undated; (1 letter)
  - Mill, John Stuart, 1869 Aug 15; (1 letter)
  - Millay, Cora B., 1915 Feb 28; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Millay, Kathleen, 1921 May 3; (1 letter)
  - Millay, Norma, 1951-1956; (10 letters, 1 postcard)
  - Miller, Harriet Mann, [1902 Jan 10?]; (1 letter)
  - Miller, Olive Thorne, undated; (3 letters)
  - Milliken, Carl E., 1917 Jul 26; (1 letter)
  - Mills, Herbert E., 1893-1927; (1 letter)
  - Milne, Daphne, undated; (2 letters)
  - Milton, John, 1667 Apr 27; (1 document facsimile)
  - Mitchell, Eliza R., 1907 May 28; (1 letter)
  - Mitchell, Maria, 1887 Jan-May; (1 letter, with accompanying letter from Israel Coe)
  - Mitchell, S. Weir, 1888 Mar 8; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Miyatovich, Cheddo, 1916 Jan 22; (1 letter)
  - Modjeska, Helena, 1902-1934; (1 diary sheet, 3 photographs, 2 envelopes, 1 letter)
  - Monnier, Mathilda, undated; (1 manuscript)
  - Monroe, Lewis B., 1875 Feb 6; (1 letter)
  - Montez, Lola, Grifin von Landsfeld, [Missing as of March 2012]
  - Montross, Lois, undated; (1 poem)
  - Montross, Lynn, 1935 Feb 22; (1 letter)
  - Moore, George, 1920 Sep; (1 letter, 1 manuscript) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Ethel, 1912-1913; (1 letter, 1 envelope, 1 note, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Moore, Eva (Perry), 1913 Jul 24; (1 letter, 1 biography, 1 envelope)
  - Moore, Frank C., 1945 Nov 13-17; (1 letter)
  - Moore, J. Stanley, 1915 Sep 27; (1 letter)
  - Moore, Virginia, 1936-1937; (2 letters)
  - Morgan, Frances T., 1921-1922; (2 letters)
  - Morgan, Louise, [no year] Aug 18; (1 letter)
  - Morgenthau, Henry, 1920-1927; (3 letters)
  - Mori, Arinori, 1871 Jul 26; (1 letter)
  - Morley, Christopher, 1920-1930; (1 letter, 1 poem, 1 addenda, 1 book leaf)
  - Morns, May, 1914-1928; (2 letters, 2 envelopes, 1 pamphlet)
  - Morrison, Ian, 1947 Nov 11; (1 letter)
  - Morse, Samuel F.B., 1814-1866; (4 letters)
  - Morse, Wayne, 1968 Jan-Feb; (1 letter)
  - Morton, Henry, 1875 Feb 3; (1 letter)
  - Morton, Levi Parsons, 1895-1901; (2 letters)
  - Mosher, Eliza M., 1885-1925; (3 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Mott, Abigail, 1847 Oct 26; (1 letter)
  - Mott, James, 1859-1862; (2 letters)
  - Mott, John R., 1917-1919; (2 letters)
  - Mott, Lucretia, 1842-1871; (12 letters)
    — Includes a letter received from George Combe about reform activities in Scotland and European revolutions (1848) as well as material on writing requests, Rochester abolitionist activities, Frederick Douglass, work of Lucy Stone and Antoinette Brown, women workers and pay inequities, work among blacks.
  - Muir, John, 1906-1937; (5 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Munday, Albert H., 1921 Mar 3; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Munger, Theodore Thorton, 1884-1889; (2 letters)
  - Murphy, Claudia Q., 1923-1926; (4 letters)
  - Murphy, Gardner, [no year] Nov 19; (1 letter)
  - Murray, Gibert, 1906-1938; (8 letters, 5 envelopes)
  - Murray, J. Middleton, 1923-1924; (3 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Murray, Pauli, 1955-1971
    — Includes material on her commencement address at Spelman College, her writing, experiences in Ghana (1961-1962), the antics of her dog, work at Yale, and fund raising to assist African law students.
  - Murrow, Janet, 1956 Nov 20; (1 letter)
  - Mus, Paul, 1950 Jun-Sep; (2 letters)
  - Muste, A.J., 1935-1938; (2 letters, 1 pamphlet)
  - Mutsu, M., 1889 Feb 15; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Mydal, Alva, 1961 Feb 13; (1 letter)
  - Myrdahl, Gunnar, undated; (1 letter)
- N
  - Nagai, Shige, 1881 Jun 21; (1 letter)
  - Napier, S., 1900 Apr 2; (1 letter)
  - Nathan, George Jean, 1924 Jul 14; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiterpartei (Nazi Party), 1941 Oct 21; (1 letter)
  - Nesmith, H. Louise, 1911 Aug 16; (1 letter)
  - Neukomm, Sigismund, Ritter von, 1825 Mar 22; (1 letter, 1 book cover)
  - New, Edmund H., 1922 Dec 23; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Newcastle, Henrietta (Goddphin), 1730 Jun 15; (1 letter)
  - Newcomb, S., 1902 Nov 28; (1 letter)
  - Newman, John P., 1888; (1 autograph)
  - Newman, Lynn, 1944-1971; (2 letters, 1 photograph)
  - Newton, Alfred Edward, 1923 May 18; (1 letter)
  - Nichols, Rose Standish, undated; (3 letters)
  - Nicholson, Meredith, 1916 Apr 8; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Nicolli, Allardyce, undated; (1 letter)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1958 Aug 27; (1 letter)
  - Niecks, Friedrich, 1897 May 25; (1 letter)
  - Nightingale, Florence, 1870 Aug 10; (1 letter)
  - Nöldeke, Wilhelm, 1864 May 9; (1 letter)
  - Nolle, Adelheid, 1898 Feb 12; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Norris, Charles G., 1921-1922; (5 letter, 1 essay)
  - North, Edward, 1875 Feb 20; (2 letters)
  - Norton, Caroline E.S., 1859 Jan 11; (3 letters)
  - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1874-1904; (2 letters)
  - Novak, Jarsolav, 1930 Jan 15; (1 letter)
  - Noyes, Albert F., 1895 Mar; (1 letter)
  - Noyes, Arthur A., 1915-1919; (2 letters)
  - Nuber, Alexander von, 1915 Jun 29; (1 letter, 2 newspaper clippings)
- O
  - Oakley, Hilda D., undated; (1 letter)
  - Oakly, Violet, 1924 Jun 17; (1 library card)
  - O’Brien, Edward J., 1926 Jan 14; (1 letter)
  - O’Day, Caroline, 1936 Feb 10; (1 letter)
  - O’Grady, Marcella I., 1895 Oct 31; (1 letter)
  - O’Keeffe, Georgia, 1944 Feb 10; (1 letter)
    — Includes letter to Eleanor Roosevelt urging her to support the equal rights amendment.
  - Olgin, Moissaye Joseph, undated; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Oliver, Wade, 1932 Jan 22; (1 letter)
  - Olmstead, Mary, 1885 Sep 10; (2 letters)
  - Olos, Robert E., 1926-1927; (3 letters)
  - Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1961-1993; (10 letters, 4 envelopes, 5 cards, 2 programs)
  - O’Neill, Eugene, 1922 Feb 14; (1 letter, 2 envelopes)
  - O’Neill, Eugene, 1933; (1 manuscript draft, 1 clipping) (Box 2)
  - Onslow, Georges, 1837 Oct 20; (1 letter)
  - Opdycke, E., 1866 Dec 17; (1 letter)
  - Opie, Amelia, 1840 May 10; (1 letter copy)
  - Oppenheim, Max von, 1932 Feb 13; (1 letter)
  - Origo, Iris, to John Sandoe, 1983-1984; (5 letters)
  - Orth, Charles D., 1921 Apr 18-29; (3 letters, 2 pamphlets, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Orton, James, 1876 Mar 20; (1 letter)
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1915-1926; (2 letters)
  - Ossoli, Margret Fuller, undated; (1 letter)
  - Owen, Robert, 1817 Apr 6; (1 letter)
  - Owen, Robert Dale, 1868-1874; (3 letters)
  - Owen, Thomas M., 1919 Feb 6; (1 letter)
- P
  - Pace, George R., 1887 Nov-Dec; (3 letters)
  - Paer, Ferdinando, 1825 Mar 30; (2 letters)
  - Page, Arthur, 1929 Nov 29; (1 letter)
  - Page, [Legh?] R., 1892 Feb-Mar; (2 letters)
  - Page, Walter H., 1908 Jan-Feb; (2 letters)
  - Pain, Barry, 1914 May 1; (1 letter)
  - Paine, Albert Bigelow, 1902 May 2; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Painter, Sidney, 1949 Jan-Sep; (2 letters)
  - Palmer, A.W., 1867 Feb 12; (1 letter)
  - Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1897-1898; (4 letters, 1 postcard)
  - Palmer, George H., 1932-1938; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Palmer, Jean C., 1916 Oct 26; (1 letter)
  - Palmer, William Kimberley, 1938 Jan 22; (1 poem)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1917 Feb 19; (1 letter)
  - Parkes, Henry, 1882 Feb 11; (1 letter)
  - Parkhurst, C.H., 1897 Mar 4; (1 letter)
  - Parmly, Duncan D., 1895 Jun 21; (1 letter)
  - Parry, Charles Hubert Hastings, 1909-1910; (2 letters)
  - Parsons, [Thomas William], "Poppies" illuminated manuscript (to Florence Cushing, VC 1874), 1891 Apr; (1 framed item) (Framed Storage 1.3)
  - Pattison, Thomas Hardwood, 1897 May 8; (1 letter)
  - Pau, General G., 1920 Nov 2; (1 letter, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Paul, Alice, 1916 Dec 27; (1 letter)
  - Paulson, Arvid, undated; (1 letter fragment)
  - Peabody, Andrew Preston, 1875 Feb 3; (1 letter, 1 clipping of letter)
  - Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer, 1840-1851; (7 letters)
    — Includes material on prayer and preaching, spiritual and religious ideas, Church affairs in Boston, and Theodore Parker.
  - Pearce, C.A., 1936 Sep-Dec; (1 letter)
  - Peckham, Elizabeth Gifford, 1905 Apr 4; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Peers, Katherine E., 1918 Sep 17; (1 letter)
  - Peers, Tracy, 1889 Sep 20; (1 letter)
  - Peirce, Katherine V., 1885 Jul 17-24; (1 letter)
  - Peirce, Waldo, 1940 Nov 7; (1 letter)
  - Pelton, Henry V., 1923 Jun 15; (1 letter)
  - Pendelton, Ellen L., 1915-1917; (2 letters)
  - Penn, N.S., 1917 Apr; (2 letters)
  - Pepper, C. Doris (Hellman), 1958 Feb-Jul; (2 letters, 1 postcard, 1 galley proof sheet, 1 memo)
  - Perkins, Emma M., 1913 Jul-Oct; (2 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Perkins, Lucy F., 1898 Nov 18; (2 letters)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E., 1930-1946; (6 letters)
  - Perry, Jeannette, 1938 Dec 21-28; (1 letter)
  - Pershing, John J., 1921 Jan 19; (1 letter)
  - Pethick-Lawrence, Helen, 1938 Nov 18; (1 letter)
  - Pethick-Lawrence, Mrs. E., 1959 Feb 23; (1 letter)
  - Petry, Dr. J, 1925 Nov 7; (1 letter, 1 note)
  - Pettridge, W., [1920 Jan 1?]; (1 letter)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1901-1925; (6 letters)
  - Phillips, Frances, 1936 Oct 26; (1 letter)
  - Phillips, John S., 1914 Feb 9-10; (2 letters)
  - Phillips, Wendell, 1964 Apr 25; (1 letter)
  - Phinney, Jessie (Woodward), 1915 Oct 31; (1 letter)
  - Pickering, Ruth, 1937 Nov 22; (1 letter)
  - Pirrotta, Nino, 1961 May 9; (1 letter)
  - Piston, Walter, 1963 May 3-8; (2 letters)
  - Plagemann, Bentz, [no year] Aug 10; (1 letter)
  - Platt, Edmund, 1917 May 26; (1 letter)
  - Platt, Louise B., 1915 Oct 19; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Playfair, Lyon, 1883 Aug 1; (1 letter)
  - Plimpton, George A., 1917 Feb-May; (7 letters)
  - Poe, Edgar Allen, undated; (1 poem)
  - Poletti, Jean (Ellis), 1942 Dec 18; (1 letter, 1 envelope, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Poppenheim, Mary B., 1922 Feb 8; (1 letter)
  - Porter, Noah, 1874 Jul 6; (1 letter)
  - Porter, Quincy, 1945-1946; (4 letters)
  - Pory, John, undated; (1 newsletter excerpt)
  - Potter, Henry Codman, 1884, 1891, 1898; (3 letters)
  - Pound, Ezra, undated; (1 letter)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1943 Oct 28; (1 letter)
  - Powell, Elizabeth M., 1867 Oct 16; (1 letter)
  - Powell, George H., 1914 Jan 7; (1 letter)
  - Powell, Roger, 1960 Jun-Nov; (2 letters)
  - Powell, Thomas Reed, 1938-1941; (3 letters)
  - Power, Eileen, 1930 Dec 22; (1 postcard)
  - Power, M., [1854 Oct 11?]; (1 clipping)
  - Power, R.G., undated; (1 letter)
  - Pratt, Richardson, 1947-1956; (3 letters, 1 list of gifts)
  - Praus, Dr. F., 1927 Aug 2; (1 letter)
  - Preston, Etta (Shield), 1939 Feb 5; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Prime, Edward D.G., 1875 Feb 10; (1 letter)
  - Prime, Samuel Irenaeus, 1875 Feb 2; (1 letter)
  - Prince, Ethel A., undated; (1 letter)
  - Prochazka, Dr. L.P., 1923 Aug 15; (1 letter)
  - Proctor, Richard A., 1874, 1886; (3 letters)
  - Prothero, G.W., 1910 Jan 25; (1 letter)
  - Prout, Ebenezer, [1897 Apr 16?]; (1 letter)
  - Pruyn, Robert Hewson, [no year] Jul 20; (1 letter)
  - Pryce, Richard, 1914 Jan 12; (1 letter)
  - Pugh, Edwin, 1914 Dec 15; (1 letter)
  - Pugh, Sarah, 1870-1881; (2 letters)
  - Pupin, Michael Idvorsky, 1916-1934; (4 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Putnam, George Haven, 1914 Feb 2; (1 letter)
  - Putnam, Herbert N., 1904-1926; (4 letters)
  - Putnam, I., 1897 Apr 9; (1 letter)
  - Putnam, Ruth, 1919; (1 letter, 1 envelope, 1 form)
  - Pynchon, Thomas Ruggies, 1875 Feb 11; (1 letter)
- Q
- R
  - Radin, Max, 1923 Mar 14; (1 letter)
  - Randolph, Beverley, 1930 Apr 21; (1 document, 1 envelope)
  - Rascher, Sigurd, 1943-1944; (2 letters, 4 envelopes, 1 pamphlet)
  - Ratcliffe, S.K., 1894 Mar-Aug; (5 letters, 2 pamphlets, 2 envelopes)
  - Raven, John H., 1909 Apr 8; (1 letter)
  - Raymond, Charles A., 1864; [Missing as of February 2023]
    — Includes material on on Vassar College and women's education.
  - Raymond, R.R., 1879 Sep 23; (1 letter)
  - Reade, Charles, 1932 Dec; (1 letter)
  - Reed, Amy L., 1913-1920; (5 letters)
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1869 Jul 6; (1 letter)
  - Reimer, Marie, 1913 Aug 22; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Remenyi, Eduard Hoffman, undated; (1 letter, 3 leafs sheet music)
  - Remsen, Ira, 1889 Dec 11-14; (1 letter)
  - Repplier, Agnes, 1913 Mar 12; (1 letter)
  - Reynolds, Myra A., 1897 Jan 19; (1 letter)
  - Rice, Fenelon B., 1897 May 29; (1 letter)
  - Richards, I.A., 1962 Oct 11-26; (2 letters)
  - Richards, T.W., 1915 Oct 30; (1 letter)
  - Richards, William T., 1861 Apr 4; (1 letter)
  - Richardson, C., [no year] Jun 23; (1 letter)
  - Richert, Conrad, 1966 May 28; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Rickert, Edith, 1900-1909; (1 letter, 1 envelope, 1 photograph, 2 illustrations)
  - Rideal, Eric K., 1949 Apr 1; (1 letter)
  - Riesser, H.E., 1923 Jul 10; (1 letter)
  - Rieti, Vittorio, 1961-1963; (9 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Riis, Jacob, 1892-1897; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Ritchie, Anne Isabella (Thackery), 1899 Jul 25; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Roberts, Kenneth, 1930 Mar 23; (1 letter)
  - Robins, Elizabeth, 1914 Jan 3; (1 letter)
  - Robinson, Ezekiel Gilman, 1875 Feb 20; (1 letter)
  - Robinson, Fred, 1961 May 26; (1 letter)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton, 1951 Jul 31; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Robinson, James Harvey, 1903 Sep 16; (1 letter)
  - Roch, Adele, 1874 Apr 10; (1 letter)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1921 Feb 23; (1 letter)
  - Rockefeller, Mary C., 1960 Dec 22; (1 letter)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1960-1964; (3 letters)
  - Rodell, Fred, 1963 Jun 18; (1 letter)
  - Roe, Edward Payson, 1888 Jul 4-17; (1 letter)
  - Rogers, Bruce, undated; (1 postage label)
  - Rogers, Roland, [no year] Apr 10; (1 letter)
  - Rohde, Eleanor Sinclair, 1933 Aug 9; (2 letters)
  - Romulo, Carlos P., 1957-1958; (2 letters)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1929-1961; (10 letters, 4 envelopes, 1 document)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1914-1940; (110 letters, 7 telegrams, 1 postcard, 2 documents, 1 envelope, 1 photograph)
  - Roosevelt, Sarah Delano, 1897 Apr 9; (2 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1890-1917; (5 letters, 1 envelope, 1 photograph, 1 copy)
  - Rose, Ernestine L., 1854-1855; (5 letters)
  - Roselli, Bruno, 1919-1941; (31 letters, 8 postcards, 3 telegrams, 2 notes)
  - Rosenburg, Anna, 1951-1954; (2 letters)
  - Rossiter & Wright, 1895 Oct 10; (1 letter)
  - Rothenstein, Sir John, 1953 Jun 5; (1 letter)
  - Round, William Manshall Fitts, [18??] Dec 13; (1 letter)
  - Rourke, Constance, 1931-1936; (16 letters, 3 documents, 1 envelope)
  - Rowse, Dr. A.L., undated; (1 letter)
  - Royal College of Surgeons, 1856 May 13-17; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Royce, Josiah, 1832 Apr 9; (1 letter)
  - Royce, Robert H., 1937 Sep 24; (1 letter)
  - Rubner, Cornelius, 1910 Nov 10; (1 letter)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, undated; [Missing as of March 2012]
  - Rulofson, Carol C., 1939 May 3-17; (3 letters)
  - Ruml, Beardsley, 1959 May-Jul; (2 letters)
  - Russell, Henry Norris, 1926 Oct-Nov; (2 letters)
  - Russell, Patricia, 1936 Aug 19; (1 letter)
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1935-1952; (23 letters, 9 envelopes, 1 pamphlet)
  - Ryberg, Inez Scott, undated; (1 letter)
  - Rye, Walter, 1908 Apr 23-27; (2 letters)
  - Ryerson, Margery A., 1977 Aug 15; (1 letter)
- S
  - Sabin, Florence R., 1926 Sep 20; (1 letter)
  - Saito, Hirosi, 1925 Dec 16; (1 letter)
  - Salisbury, Lord, 1943 Sep 6; (1 signature, 2 illustrations, 2 copies of a letter)
  - Salmon, Lucy M., 1888-1925; (61 letters, 36 envelopes, 8 notes, 5 documents, 1 newspaper clipping)
    — Includes material on Vassar College History Dept., labor issues, and personal news.
  - Salvermini, G., 1933-1938; (2 letters)
  - Salvini, Tommaso, 1889 Dec 6; (1 letter)
  - Sample, Paul, 1940 Nov 8; (2 letters)
  - San Juan, Marquis of, 1883 Sep 15; (1 letter)
  - Sanborn, Frank B., 1882 Jul 11; (1 letter, 1 copy)
  - Sanchez, Oscar Arias, 1987 Nov 9; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1921-1922; (3 letters)
  - Sandys, Sir John Edwin, 1904 Dec 30; (1 letter)
  - Sanford, Mary R., 1913-1941; (2 letters)
  - Sanger, Margaret, 1935-1937; (2 letters)
  - Sangster, Margaret E., 1900 Jan 27; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Sargent, John, 1864 Jan 21; (1 copy of a letter)
  - Sarton, George, 1917-1918; (3 letters)
  - Saunders, Fredrick, 1930 Apr 13; (1 letter)
  - Sawyer, Harriet, 1925 Mar 25-28; (2 letters)
  - Schacht, Hjalmar, 1933 Apr 20; (1 letter)
  - Schaff, Philip, 1875 Feb 4; (1 letter)
  - Schauffler, Robert Haven, 1911 Nov 7; (1 letter)
  - Schenck, Charles L., 1924-1925; (2 letters)
  - Schermerhorn, Elizabeth W., 1939 Jul 25; (2 letters)
  - Scheu-Rusz, Helene, 1926 May-Jun; (3 letters)